America is being born again.
Jesus Camp is a documentary film directed by Heidi Ewing.
Jesus Camp is a Christian summer camp where children hone their "prophetic
gifts" and are schooled in how to "take back America for Christ".
The film is a first-ever look into an intense training ground that recruits born-again
Christian children to become an active part of America's political future.
Self, played by Becky Fischer.
Self, played by Mike Papantonio.
Self, played by Ted Haggard.
Self, played by Lou Engle.
Jesus Camp is a 2006 American documentary film directed by Rachel Grady and Heidi Ewing about a charismatic Christian summer camp,
where children spend their summers being taught that they have "prophetic gifts" and can "take back America for Christ".
According to the distributor, it "doesn't come with any prepackaged point of view" and attempts to be "an
honest and impartial depiction of one faction of the evangelical Christian community".
Jesus Camp premiered at the 2006 Tribeca Film Festival, and was
sold by A&E Indie Films to Magnolia Pictures.
Nominated for Best Documentary Feature at the 79th Academy Awards, the film
brought controversy to the camp which led to its eventual closure.
The film explores themes of summer camp, religious
education, christianity, conservatism, god.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.